Karoun Kasraie

Web Developer

www.karoun.me contact@karoun.me github.com/karoun

About

Karoun Kasraie is a self-taught web developer and current full-time student. He has a passion for building great experiences and products with an eye for detail and tendency toward perfectionism.

Skills

He enjoys a hot cup of chai, a good book, and good horn band. Front-End Back-End Server

Expertise in front-end development paradigms, including responsive grids, HTML5, CSS3, and various Javascript libraries.

Extensive experience with various server-side languages and frameworks from PHP to Ruby on Rails, for apps, websites, and CMS conversions.

Numerous site launches on both Nginx and Apache, with auto-deployment from Github, Bash scripting, and CDN/Varnish integration.

Technology

HTML5, CSS3, Javascript PHP, Python, Node.js, Ruby Responsive/Adaptive Design MySQL, PostgreSQL, NoSQL AJAX, Single-page apps Nginx, Apache, Bash

OS X 10.4 - 10.8 Windows XP - 7 *nix

Experience

National Public Radio

2011 - Present

Digital Media Intern

Along with Agile development team, rolled out permissioning system for NPR story API and Github-hosted documentation for the same.

Developed an interactive query builder for the above API using Knockout.js, which provides developer with immediate feedback and API output, based on various API parameters.

Implemented responsive multimedia website for Intern Edition radio show, the first in that program's history.

The Daily Californian

Online Manager

Responsible for upkeep of 111,000+ article, award-winning university news website, dailycal.org, with over a dozen subdomains and numerous content sources.

Conducted transition of the same to a WordPress network hosted on Nginx, implemented a responsive grid system and new design, and developed numerous plugins for various sitespecific functionality.

Replaced paper job applications with online application infrastructure, utilizing Dropbox and Google Spreadsheets.

Tellefsen Hall

2009 - 2011

Network Manager

Researched, initiated, and oversaw installation of a blanket wireless-N solution for a 5000 sq. ft facility. Maintained and improved a complex network, servicing over 40 concurrent users.

Updated website, tellefsenhall.org, with a brand-new design, graphics, and identity and transitioned backend from plain HTML to WordPress.

University of California Marching Band

2009 - Present

Member, Computer Committee

Integrated 60+ page HTML website, calband.berkeley.edu, with WordPress for easy updating and maintenance.

Redesigned and implemented a new, AJAX-enabled, backwards-compatible login form using PHP, HTML, CSS, and jQuery.

Working with a 6-member team to redesign and rewrite large internal-use application. Wrote database design and accompanying ER diagrams, SQL schema, etc.

Ventura College

2007 - 2010

Web Developer, Student Technician

Responsible for maintaining external website, venturacollege.edu, using the OmniUpdate CMS, providing phone support to over 300 faculty, acting as primary Mac OS X field technician, and creating and maintaining an AJAX-enabled faculty phone/email directory.

Self-Employed

2004 - Present

Freelance Web Developer and Consultant

Worked with a variety of clients to create CMS-enabled web presences, gave consultations regarding professional equipment and services, and built custom desktop workstations.

Portfolio available at www.karoun.me upon request; website is under construction.

Education

University of California, Berkeley, '13

3.1 **GPA**

Computer Science, Music (minor)

Ventura College, '09

3.8 **GPA**

72 Credit-hours

El Camino High School, '09

4.3 **GPA**

Valedictorian